Jeffrey Allen Ohrt

MBA / PhD Risk & Crisis Management (in process)

M.Engineering (2000), M.A. Applied Linguistics (2006)

Hons. Bachelor of Science in Agriculture.(1997)

Trades → Structural Welder (ITA Lvl 1 & 2)

Professional Summary

I have been employed in the logistics, supervision, teaching and training in educational contexts since 1992. My primary responsibilities focus on the supervision of staff, logistics and supply chain aspects of project based contracts in international contexts. My primary responsibilities also include fabrication of equipment and resources where my specialties are in Resistant Materials and welding.

My secondary responsibilities focus on physical and mental health and safety particularly in rural and challenging international contexts. The last 15 years have focused on international education as a teaching administrator or consultant, particularly the Cambridge Suite, International Baccalaureate, US Common Core and US Advanced Placement curricula where I hold 40 qualifications in more than a dozen international curricula.

As an extension of my international employment, I run an informal private foundation called That's IT. This work began in 1995 and continues to this day.

Core Qualifications

- → Management & Supervision (150 staff)
- → Research and Publication (60+ items)
- → International Workshops (200+)
- → Advanced Computer, Coding and Internet skills

- → US Clinical Supervisor & Teaching licenses
- → Canadian licensed Structural Welder
- → TESOL & TEFL (lvl 3 permanent)
- → Design and Technology Resistant Materials

Experience

Staff Intervention and Conflict Resolution (1992 - 2017)

→ As a subset of my supervision and training responsibilities I have been regularly employed to investigate, intervene and resolve interpersonal and intercultural conflict.

Staff Supervision, Training and Teaching (2004 - 2017)

- → National and International Teacher training and supervision in 16 countries.
- → Cambridge, International Baccalaureate, US Common Core and US Advanced Placement curricula

Staff Supervision and Training (1994 - 2004)

- → Forestry (planting, burning and power saw) and related skills
- → Onsite Paramedic (Lvl 3 IFA Industrial First Aid Unrestricted)

Staff Supervision and Training (1992 - 1997)

- → Dalhousie University (Nova Scotia Agricultural College)
- → Nova Scotia Department of Agriculture and Marketing

Charitable Contributions

That's IT (1995 - present)

- → That's IT provides training manuals and related e-resources free of advertising and related barriers to information.
- → That's IT provides staff training and resources in rural and challenging environments internationally. There is a particular focus on providing IT and ICT infrastructure and support in environments that have logistical constraints to traditional infrastructure.

Education

MBA / PhD (in process)

- → Risk & Crisis Management
- → 2017 LIGS University, Hawaii
- → 2016 SMC University, Switzerland

MBA / PhD (1 yr)

- → Information Security, Risk and Crisis Management
- → Swiss Management University, Zugg, Switzerland

M. Engineering (2001)

- → Biological Water Treatment
- → Lenox Institute, USA

MA Applied Linguistics (2006)

- → Computational Linguistics
- → University of New England, Australia

B.Sc.Agr. (1997)

- → Agricultural / Biological Sciences and Engineering
- → Dalhousie University, Canada

<u>Licenses & Certificates</u>

- → US Teaching Licenses
 - K-12 ICT, 4-12 Sciences, 4-8 Maths
- → US Teaching Clinical Supervisor
 - K-12

- → TESL Level 3 Permanent
- → TESOL
- → Cambridge Speaking Examiner
- → 40 STEM and Design & Technology related teaching qualifications